In this video, we will share with you the techniques and problem-solving solutions of the automatic adjustment board tool group.
The automatic adjustment board tool can allow you to reuse assets on multiple projects or models.
Please remember, when you need to use the automatic adjustment board function, please try to make the lines and structures of the clothing as simple as possible, and avoid too much fine-tuning before using this function.
For example, for the bottom of this skirt, I need to make it level, because if it is adapted to multiple models, the original line may become more and more crooked.
In addition, if I want to set up a file that needs to be automatically adjusted on the outside of the skirt, such as a sweater, but this sweater has not used the automatic adjustment board function, and the skirt has already used it.
We suggest that we set up another project for the sweater.
In this case, we will use the automatic adjustment board function.
Because if there is already another dress in the scene, and then use the automatic adjustment board for the new dress, it may cause the position or size of the clothes to change.
I will use the automatic adjustment board tool to let you check the possible problems that may occur.
After completion, we will see that the board has been modified.
Hiding the sweater, we will see some changes in this skirt, which is not the effect we want.
You will find that the front and back of this skirt are different.
At the same time, it may cause such problems when using the automatic adjustment board for the clothes that have already been modified and those that have not been automatically adjusted.
Therefore, if you want to automatically adjust the files in multiple projects, please try to separate the automatic adjustment and then integrate them together.
If you encounter this notification when trying to use the automatic adjustment board tool, and only use the pre-registered virtual model, then there are two things to be confirmed.
Is there a virtual model in this project?
Is there a virtual model on your virtual model?
Please confirm that there is a virtual model in the current project.
If not, please import one.
Then go to the virtual model display option in the 3D window.
Click on the virtual model display to see if there is a virtual model in the virtual model.
If there is no black grid-like virtual model around your virtual model, then please use the creative virtual model tool to create a virtual model for your virtual model.
If there is a clothing file in your current scene,
when you choose to create a virtual model for your virtual model, a prompt will pop up.
The file has not been saved. Do you want to save the file?
In this video, I will choose no.
Then the clothing in the work area will be deleted.
The history record has also been deleted.
If you have just saved the clothing or project file and have not modified it afterwards, you will not receive this prompt.
Your clothing has been emptied.
Since you have saved it before, it will not prompt you to perform the operation of saving again.
Only after the clothing is emptied can you normally use the creative virtual model tool.
In the work area, you need no clothing to add the information for the virtual model.
Since the clothing and history records will be emptied, please save your project file before using this function.
We recommend that you directly create a project, enter the virtual model file, and start creating a virtual model.
If you want to use the automatic wear or automatic adjustment version, the prompt pops up.
Only the clothing that is used for simulation is used.
Usually, this means that the current clothing does not have the information for creating a virtual model.
Therefore, please check it.
Please go to the 3D display window.
In the clothing display option, click on the display clothing to check.
Here I open the display clothing, but you will find that there is no clothing with a red grid in our scene.
Because this set of clothing is an old file I made in Marvelous Designer 8 or 7, so it does not have the information for wearing clothes.
If your clothing file does not have the information for wearing clothes, such as the one downloaded from the website or the old version of Marvelous Designer 8 or 7.
In this case, the clothing cannot use the automatic adjustment version or automatic wear directly.
If you want to solve this problem, please wear the clothing in the model with the information for wearing clothes.
In the current version, the MoYue virtual model that our software brings with it is with the information for wearing clothes.
Therefore, here I will simulate the clothing on the male virtual model brought by the software.
After the simulation is complete, I will save the clothing file again.
Before saving the file, you will not be able to see it.
Before saving the file, you will not be able to see the information for wearing clothes on the clothing.
I will save the whole project file and then open this file again to let you see the information for wearing clothes.
When I open this file again, you will see the red grid structure around the clothing.
This is the information for wearing clothes.
Thank you for watching this tutorial.
If you have any tutorials or questions, please leave a message in the comments section below.
See you in the next video, bye.
Thank you for watching this video.